#### brian.d.pemberton@gmail.com

Pemby.github.io

linkedin.com/in/brpemberton/

# **Brian Pemberton**

# **SKILLS**

I am a technical support professional with tenacity to solve problems using technology and automation. I have demonstrated a history of working in the primary/secondary education industry. I am skilled in hardware and software repair, system administration and computer programming. I am experienced in setting up development environments, network stacks, web servers, MDM server-client configurations. I have development experience using OOP and MVC paradigms with the following software frameworks: JavaFX, Django, and .NET.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Portland Public Schools, Portland OR** — Instructional Technology Assistant

February 2014 - PRESENT

- Troubleshoot, diagnose, repair computer hardware, software, networks, and peripheral equipment.
- Technical support to staff, students, and community members via telephone, virtually, remote and in-person.
- Audio Visual support and for live performances and events. Micing, mixing, lighting, soundboards, and post-production.
- Supervised, trained, and managed student-run technology support teams that focused on tech support and technology projects.
- Supervised a computer lab of students before, during, and after school, emphasizing exploring and experimenting with computers and technology.
- Maintain positive relationships with staff, students, and community members and keep open office hours for technical support meetings.

### The Mac Store, Portland OR - Macologist

June 2009 - Dec 2014

- I streamlined help desk processes by creating scripts and software for repeated procedures.
- Helped formulate the help desk processes by coaching my team to use note templates that focused on consistency and including all relevant information.
- Specialized in software imaging deployments and in logical data recovery.
- I was consistently able to fix complex problems and mend relationships with people and their technology.

# Apple Inc, Santa Clara, & New York, NY- Genius

June 2006 - May 2009

- Work with a full spectrum of customers, from brand new users to Apple Professional customers.
- Responsible for constant changes in technical knowledge.
- Multi-tasking under a tight appointment system.
- Working with a team and the daily practice of fine-tuning empathy skills, patience, and listening.
- Aligning with customer concerns while offering non-intrusive solutions.
- Setting clear expectations about service outcomes.
- Documenting all service-related steps in a CRM-Ticketing software

### **EDUCATION**

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City UT — Bachelor of Science — Computer Science

2018 - 2020

**Portland Community College, Portland OR** — Associate of Applied Science - Computer Information Systems

2014 - 2016

### **Certifications**

CompTIA - Project+ Certification
2020

**Portland Community College** — *Linux Server Administration* 2016

**Apple** — Certified Macintosh Technician (ACMT) Certification 2007-2013

Digidesign — Certified Pro Tools Operator 2005